Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're going to be talking about a very special topic.
今天我们要讨论一个非常特别的话题。
That's right.
没错。
This topic was actually suggested by one of our listeners.
这个话题实际上是由我们的一位听众建议的。
Exactly.
正是如此。
So keep those comments coming because we want to create lessons that you need, that
所以请继续提出你们的意见，因为我们想创建你们需要、你们想要的课程。
you want.
你们想要的。
Exactly.
没错。
So what are we talking about today?
那我们今天要谈什么？
Today's lesson is about applying for a visa.
今天的课程是关于申请签证。
A very, very important topic.
一个非常重要的话题。
Yes.
是的。
And specifically, it's about a visa interview.
具体来说，是关于签证面试。
Exactly.
没错。
As you all probably know, when you apply for a visa, especially for the US, you have an
大家可能都知道，当你申请签证时，尤其是美国签证，你会有一个
interview.
面试。
Yes.
是的。
Where you have to answer some questions.
你必须回答一些问题。
Yes.
是的。
And that's what we're going to be talking about today.
这就是我们今天要讨论的内容。
So before we jump into the dialogue, let's take a look at vocabulary preview.
所以在进入对话之前，我们先来看一下词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Okay.
好的。
So let's talk about visa.
那么我们来谈谈签证。
Right.
对。
A visa, it's not a credit card.
签证，它不是信用卡。
No, not visa or MasterCard.
不，不是维萨卡或万事达卡。
No.
不是。
A visa is an official document that you get in your passport that allows you to travel
签证是一种官方文件，你把它放在护照里，可以让你合法地
legally to a country.
前往某个国家。
Exactly.
没错。
So with this document, you can go into a country.
所以有了这个文件，你就可以进入一个国家。
Okay.
好的。
So we have different types of visas.
我们有不同类型的签证。
Today we're going to be talking about a B2 visa.
今天我们要讨论的是B2签证。
Right.
对。
A B2 visa is a tourist visa.
B2签证是一种旅游签证。
A tourist visa.
旅游签证。
Yeah.
是的。
This is only for the United States.
这只适用于美国。
Other countries may have different classifications for their visas, but B2 is for the United
其他国家可能对签证有不同分类，但B2是针对美国的。
States.
美国。
Right.
对。
So we have a tourist visa when we want to be a tourist and just travel in the US.
所以当我们想以游客身份去美国旅行时，我们持有旅游签证。
What about a resident visa?
那居民签证呢？
Well, you can have a temporary resident visa.
嗯，你可以持有临时居民签证。
Like for example, an F1.
比如，F1签证。
Yep.
是的。
An F1 is for foreign exchange students who go and live in the States maybe for a year
F1签证是针对去美国生活可能一年的外国交换生
or do a MBA for two years or three years.
或者读两年或三年的MBA。
So that's an F1 visa.
所以那是F1签证。
You can also get a J1 visa, which is a temporary exchange visitor.
你还可以获得J1签证，这是一种临时交流访问者签证。
Okay.
好的。
So that would be to maybe do some temporary work for two or three months and then go back
所以那可能是去做两三个月的临时工作，然后返回
to your country.
你的国家。
So basically a resident visa allows you to live in that country.
所以基本上，居留签证允许你居住在那个国家。
Yeah.
是的。
You can live in that country legally for a determined time.
你可以在那个国家合法居住一段时间。
Okay.
好的。
So let's listen to our dialogue.
那么我们来听一下对话。
Where are we going to be exactly?
我们具体要去哪里？
In this dialogue, we're going to hear two people, a visa officer and a person who's
在这个对话中，我们会听到两个人，一位签证官和一位申请签证的人。
applying for the visa.
申请签证的人。
Now, the person who's applying for the visa has an accent, right?
现在，申请签证的人有口音，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
So that's really good practice for helping you to understand people with different accents.
所以这真的是很好的练习，帮助你理解不同口音的人。
Exactly.
没错。
So let's listen to the dialogue and then we'll come back and explain all the great vocabulary.
那么我们来听一下对话，然后回来解释所有精彩的词汇。
So you're applying for a B2 visa.
所以你是来申请B2签证的。
Where's your final destination and what's the purpose of your trip to the United States?
你的最终目的地是哪里？你去美国的目的是什么？
I'm going to visit my brother.
我要去看我哥哥。
He's just had a baby.
他刚生了个孩子。
He lives in Minneapolis.
他住在明尼阿波利斯。
And how long do you plan to remain in the United States?
你打算在美国待多久？
I'll be here for approximately three weeks.
我大概会在这里待三周。
So here's my return ticket for the 26th of March.
这是我的回程机票，3月26日的。
And who's sponsoring your trip?
谁为你这次旅行提供资助？
My brother here.
我哥哥在这里。
This is an invitation letter from him.
这是他写的邀请信。
I will stay with him and his family in their home.
我会和他以及他的家人住在他家里。
All right.
好的。
Tell me about the ties you have to your home country.
跟我说说你和母国的联系。
Well, I own a house.
嗯，我有一栋房子。
Actually, I'm leaving my dog there with my neighbors.
实际上，我把我的狗留在邻居那里了。
I have a car at home.
我在家有一辆车。
I know my job.
我知道我的工作。
I'm employed by Tornell as an engineer.
我在Tornell公司担任工程师。
Actually, I only have three week vacation.
实际上，我只有三周假期。
So I have to go back to work at the end of March.
所以我必须在三月底回去工作。
And what evidence do you have that you are financially independent?
你有什么证据证明你经济独立？
Well, I do have assets in my country.
嗯，我在国内确实有资产。
Like I said, I own a house and see, here's a bank statement showing my investments and
就像我说的，我有一栋房子，你看，这是一份银行对账单，显示我的投资和
my bank balance.
我的账户余额。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
We cannot grant you a B2 visa at this time.
我们目前无法批准你的B2签证。
Instead, you are granted a resident visa.
相反，你获得了居民签证。
Congratulations.
恭喜你。
You are the millionth person to apply for a visa.
你是第100万个申请签证的人。
You win.
你赢了。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
All right.
好的。
What a lucky guy.
真是个幸运的家伙。
He applied for a tourist visa and now he's getting a resident visa.
他申请旅游签证，现在却拿到了居民签证。
Yeah, that's that's great.
是啊，那真是太棒了。
But does this really happen?
但这真的会发生吗？
No.
不会。
No, no.
不，不会。
It doesn't happen at a consulate.
在领事馆不会发生这种事。
Okay.
好吧。
Well, we can we can dream that this might happen for us.
嗯，我们可以梦想这种事发生在我们身上。
Yeah, exactly.
是啊，没错。
All right.
好的。
Let's take a look at the words in Language Takeaway today.
我们来看看今天的“语言要点”中的单词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
On Language Takeaway, we have sponsoring.
在“语言要点”中，我们有“赞助”。
Sponsoring.
赞助。
担保。
Sponsoring.
So, Erika, what does it mean to sponsor somebody?
那么，Erika，担保某人是什么意思？
When you sponsor somebody for a visa, you take care of them and make sure they have
当你为某人的签证做担保时，你要照顾他们，并确保他们有
enough money.
足够的钱。
Okay.
好的。
So, you are the one who's responsible for all of their expenses and making sure they
所以，你是负责他们所有开销并确保他们
just have enough money.
有足够钱的人。
Okay.
好的。
So, for example, when I was 16, I made a trip to another country.
比如，我16岁时去另一个国家旅行。
Yep.
嗯。
And my parents were my sponsors.
我的父母就是我的担保人。
So, they took responsibility for your money.
所以他们负责你的钱。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Let's look at our next word.
我们来看下一个词。
Invitation Letter.
邀请函。
Now, this is a really important part for a visa application.
这是签证申请中非常重要的一部分。
Yes.
是的。
Very important.
非常重要。
What is an Invitation Letter?
什么是邀请函？
Well, an Invitation Letter is a formal letter that a friend or a relative or maybe a business
邀请函是一封正式的信函，由朋友、亲戚或企业
writes to ask you to come to their country.
写来邀请你去他们的国家。
Exactly.
没错。
So, you're being invited for a specific purpose to the United States.
所以你是因为特定目的被邀请到美国的。
Yeah.
对。
And you have to give this letter to the visa officer.
你必须把这封信交给签证官。
Okay.
好的。
Invitation Letter.
邀请函。
Our next word.
下一个词。
Ties.
纽带。
What are ties?
什么是纽带？
It looks exactly like tie, like the one you wear in your suit.
它看起来就像领带，你西装上戴的那种。
Not quite the same though.
但意思不完全一样。
All right.
好吧。
So, what are ties?
那么，什么是纽带？
The ties you have to your country are the things that keep you attached to your country.
你和国家的纽带就是那些让你与祖国保持联系的东西。
Okay.
好的。
That make sure that you will return to your country.
它们确保你会回到你的国家。
Okay.
好的。
So, what are some examples of ties?
那么，纽带有哪些例子呢？
Like maybe a house or a wife or a child or maybe some money in your bank account.
比如房子、妻子、孩子，或者银行账户里的钱。
Okay.
好的。
Or a job even.
甚至是一份工作。
Okay.
好的。
So, a good way to think of this is imagine like a rope that's attached to you and tying
所以，一个很好的理解方式就是想象有一根绳子系在你身上，
you to your country, to your house, to your job, to your kids.
把你和你的国家、你的房子、你的工作、你的孩子绑在一起。
Okay.
好的。
So, you can't run away.
这样你就跑不掉了。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
That was clear but let's listen to some more examples of how we would use ties.
这很清楚，但让我们听更多关于如何使用“纽带”的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
I sold my house and closed my bank account.
我卖掉了房子，注销了银行账户。
I don't have any more ties to my home country.
我和祖国再也没有任何纽带了。
Example two.
例子二。
Alvin enjoyed being single.
阿尔文享受单身生活。
He wasn't ready for the ties of family life.
他还没准备好接受家庭生活的束缚。
Example three.
例子三。
Diplomatic relations have improved and the ties between the two countries are stronger.
外交关系改善了，两国之间的纽带更加牢固了。
Alright.
好了。
It's clear now.
现在清楚了。
Let's look at our next word.
我们来看下一个词。
Financially independent.
经济独立。
So that means that you don't need anyone.
这意味着你不需要依赖任何人。
That you have enough money.
你有足够的钱。
You have enough money for yourself.
你有足够的钱养活自己。
Right.
对。
So, you don't have to ask your parents to pay for your ticket or pay for your food or
所以，你不必让父母帮你付机票钱或饭钱，
whatever.
等等。
Okay.
好的。
And our last word for today.
今天最后一个词。
Assets.
资产。
Okay.
好的。
So, your assets are kind of like your ties.
所以，你的资产有点像你的纽带。
Right.
对。
So, things of value that you own.
就是你拥有的有价值的东西。
Things that are expensive that you own in your home country.
你在本国拥有的昂贵物品。
So, it would be a house.
比如房子。
Yep.
嗯。
A car.
汽车。
Yep.
嗯。
Maybe stocks.
也许还有股票。
Stocks.
股票。
Or investments.
或者投资。
Okay.
好的。
So, all of those things are your assets.
所以，这些都是你的资产。
Okay.
好的。
So, we've seen a lot of great words and I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue
我们学到了很多好词，我觉得是时候再听一遍我们的对话了。
again.
再听一遍。
We're going to slow it down for you.
我们会放慢语速。
Yeah.
是的。
So, you'll understand it a little bit better.
这样你就能更好地理解。
So you're applying for a B2 visa.
所以你在申请B2签证。
Where is your final destination and what is the purpose of your trip to the United States?
你的最终目的地是哪里？你去美国的目的是什么？
I'm going to visit my brother.
我去看望我哥哥。
He's just had a baby.
他刚生了个孩子。
He lives in Minneapolis.
他住在明尼阿波利斯。
Because how long do you plan to remain in the United States?
那你打算在美国待多久？
I'll be here for approximately three weeks.
我大概会待三周。
See, here's my return ticket for the 26th of March.
看，这是我3月26日的回程票。
And who is sponsoring your trip?
谁资助你的旅行？
My brother.
我哥哥。
Here.
给。
This is an invitation letter from him.
这是他写的邀请信。
I'll stay with him and his family in their home.
我会和他以及他的家人住在一起。
All right.
好的。
Tell me about the ties you have to your home country.
跟我说说你和本国的联系。
Well, I own a house.
嗯，我有一栋房子。
Actually I'm leaving my dog there with my neighbors.
实际上我把我的狗留给邻居照看了。
I have a car at home.
我家里有辆车。
I know, my job.
我知道，我的工作。
I'm employed by Torneo as an engineer.
我在Torneo公司担任工程师。
Actually, I only have three weeks vacation.
实际上，我只有三周假期。
So I have to go back to work at the end of March.
所以我三月底就得回去上班。
And what evidence do you have that you are financially independent?
你有什么证据证明你经济独立？
Well, I do have assets in my country.
嗯，我在国内确实有资产。
Like I said, I own a house.
就像我说的，我有一栋房子。
And see, here's a bank statement showing my investments and my bank balance.
你看，这是银行对账单，显示了我的投资和账户余额。
I'm sorry, sir.
抱歉，先生。
We cannot grant you a B2 visa at this time.
我们目前无法为您签发B2签证。
Instead, you are granted a resident visa.
相反，您将获得居留签证。
Congratulations!
恭喜！
You are the millionth person to apply for a visa.
您是第100万个申请签证的人。
You win!
您赢了！
Congratulations!
恭喜！
Yay!
耶！
Okay, today we're not going to do a regular toolkit like fluency builder or putting it
好的，今天我们不做常规的工具包，比如流利度训练或综合练习。
together.
不，我们今天要做点不一样的。
No, we're going to do something a little bit different today.
We're going to talk about the questions you will probably be asked at an interview for
我们要聊一聊面试中你可能会被问到的问题。
a US visa.
一张美国签证。
Yes.
是的。
And the useful language that you can use to answer these questions in a good way.
还有你可以用来好好回答这些问题的实用语言。
Okay, so let's take a look at our first question.
好的，那我们来看看第一个问题。
Where is your final destination and what is the purpose of your trip to the United States?
您的最终目的地是哪里？您此次前往美国的目的是什么？
So this is probably going to be the first question the interviewer is going to ask you.
所以这很可能是面试官会问你的第一个问题。
Yeah, so Marco, I know you have a lot of experience with US visas.
是的，Marco，我知道你在美国签证方面经验丰富。
How should we answer this question?
我们该怎么回答这个问题？
Well, it depends on what you're doing, right?
嗯，这取决于你做什么，对吧？
So, if you're a tourist, you would say, I'm going on vacation to New York or anywhere.
所以，如果你是游客，你会说，我要去纽约或任何地方度假。
Also, if you're visiting a family member, like in our dialogue, you would say, oh, I'm
另外，如果你去拜访家人，就像我们对话中那样，你会说，哦，我要
going to visit my sister or my brother or my cousin.
去看我的姐姐、哥哥或表亲。
If you're applying for a business visa, then you would say, oh, I'm going to visit a company
如果你申请商务签证，那么你会说，哦，我要去拜访一家公司
or etc.
等等。
So you just have to say why you are going to the States.
所以你只需要说明你为什么去美国。
Now, is it important to be really specific?
那么，具体一点很重要吗？
Yeah, the more specific you are, it's probably better.
是的，越具体可能越好。
So if you can name the state and the city where you're going, it's much better.
所以如果你能说出你要去的州和城市，那就更好了。
Okay.
好的。
So let's listen to our next question.
那么我们来听下一个问题。
How long do you plan to remain in the United States?
你计划在美国停留多久？
Okay, so this is a really important question also because in your application, you have
好的，这也是一个非常重要的问题，因为在你的申请中，你
to put how long you plan to stay in the US.
必须填写你计划在美国停留多久。
Right.
对。
It's a pretty straightforward answer.
答案相当直接。
You know, two months, one month, three weeks.
你知道，两个月、一个月、三周。
Right.
对。
But you just have to make sure that your answer matches what's written in your application
但你得确保你的回答与申请表上写的内容一致
form.
表格。
Yeah, exactly.
对，没错。
Okay, now let's take a look at our last question.
好了，现在我们来看最后一个问题。
Tell me about the ties you have to your home country.
说说你和母国之间的联系。
Well, I think this is maybe the most important question that they'll ask you, right?
嗯，我觉得这可能是他们会问的最重要的问题，对吧？
Yeah, this is the most important question.
是的，这是最重要的问题。
This is what the interviewer is most interested in.
这是面试官最感兴趣的问题。
Okay.
好的。
So why is he interested in this?
那他为什么对这个感兴趣？
Because he has to be sure that you will not become an illegal immigrant to the United
因为他必须确保你不会成为美国的非法移民，
States.
确保你会返回你的祖国。
So that you will return to your home country.
这样你就会回到你的祖国。
Exactly.
没错。
He or she has to be convinced that you're going to return to your home country.
他或她必须确信你会返回你的祖国。
So how can you convince him?
那你怎样才能说服他呢？
Basically, by demonstrating your ties.
基本上，通过展示你的联系。
So showing the things that will pull you back to your home country.
也就是展示那些会把你拉回祖国的因素。
So if you take documents to support this, bank statements, maybe a copy of your mortgage.
所以如果你带文件来支持这一点，比如银行对账单，可能还有你的抵押贷款副本。
Yeah, like maybe your wedding certificate.
是啊，比如你的结婚证。
I don't know, even a letter from your office, from your job.
我不知道，甚至一封来自你办公室或工作的信。
So that shows that you have to return to your work.
这样能证明你必须回去工作。
The more things you bring, the better, even though the interviewer might not ask for the
你带的材料越多越好，即使面试官可能不会要求看这些
documents.
文件。
Okay, it's just better to be safe, right?
好吧，安全起见总是好的，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So come with a huge file full of things.
所以带一个装满材料的大文件夹来。
Exactly.
没错。
I've had friends who've arrived to the embassy with a huge file of documents and weren't
我有朋友去大使馆时带了一大堆文件，结果并没有
asked to show any of the documents.
被要求出示任何文件。
But other interviewers will maybe ask for it.
但其他面试官可能会要求提供。
Okay, so now let's listen to the dialogue again.
好的，现在让我们再听一遍对话。
And you'll hear how our traveler answers these questions.
你会听到我们的旅行者如何回答这些问题。
So you're applying for a B2 visa.
所以你是在申请B2签证。
Where's your final destination and what's the purpose of your trip to the United States?
你的最终目的地是哪里？你去美国的目的是什么？
I'm going to visit my brother.
我要去看我哥哥。
He's just had a baby.
他刚生了个孩子。
He lives in Minneapolis.
他住在明尼阿波利斯。
And how long do you plan to remain in the United States?
你计划在美国停留多久？
I'll be here for approximately three weeks.
我大概会待三周。
So here's my return ticket for the 26th of March.
这是我的回程机票，3月26日的。
And who's sponsoring your trip?
谁资助你的旅行？
My brother here.
我哥哥。
This is an invitation letter from him.
这是他写的邀请信。
I will stay with him and his family in their home.
我会和他以及他的家人住在一起。
All right.
好的。
Tell me about the ties you have to your home country.
说说你和母国的联系。
Well, I own a house.
嗯，我有一栋房子。
Actually, I'm leaving my dog there with my neighbors.
实际上，我把我的狗留给邻居照看了。
I have a car at home.
我在国内有辆车。
I know my job.
我知道我的工作。
I'm employed by Tornell as an engineer.
我在Tornell公司担任工程师。
Actually, I only have three week vacation.
实际上，我只有三周假期。
So I have to go back to work at the end of March.
所以我必须在三月底回去工作。
And what evidence do you have that you are financially independent?
你有什么证据证明你有经济能力？
Well, I do have assets in my country.
嗯，我在国内确实有资产。
Like I said, I own a house and see, here's a bank statement showing my investments and
就像我说的，我有一栋房子，看，这是银行对账单，显示我的投资和
my bank balance.
我的账户余额。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
We cannot grant you a B2 visa at this time.
我们目前无法批准你的B2签证。
Instead, you are granted a resident visa.
相反，你获得了居民签证。
Congratulations.
恭喜你。
You are the millionth person to apply for a visa.
你是第100万个申请签证的人。
You win.
你赢了。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
Well, I hope this was a useful lesson for all of our listeners because I'm sure that
嗯，希望这堂课对各位听众有用，因为我相信
in one point or another, in the future, you're going to apply for a visa.
将来某个时候，你们也会申请签证。
So now you know all the language that you need to more or less answer all these questions
现在你们知道了所有需要的语言，基本上可以回答
that you're going to be asked.
你们会被问到的这些问题了。
Yes.
是的。
And I'm sure that people have already applied for visas for the US, right?
而且我肯定已经有人申请了去美国的签证，对吧？
Probably, yeah.
很可能，是的。
And I want to hear from our users any stories that they have about applying for a visa.
我想听听我们的用户关于申请签证的任何故事。
Yeah, that would be great.
是的，那太好了。
I know that I have some stories to share on the comments board.
我知道我有些故事可以在评论区分享。
And we want to hear your questions and comments and any suggestions.
我们想听听你们的问题、评论和任何建议。
So visit our website at EnglishPod.com and Marco and I will be there to respond to you
所以请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，我和 Marco 会在那里回复你
and answer your questions.
并回答你的问题。
Well, everyone, thanks for listening and until next time.
好了，各位，感谢收听，下次再见。
Bye.
再见。